Guide to the Kenneth Farrand Simpson Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Personal Papers and Photographs, 1900-1983; Series V
  The series also includes papers of other family members and, to a limited extent, documents Helen Simpson's activities, particularly after her husband's death. In her files there is a small amount of personal correspondence including a letter of condolence from President Roosevelt and a few letters from Alice B. Toklas. Photographs, which are at the end of the series, include pictures of Simpson and his family, as well as Simpson at various political and civic events.
  - Address book and guest list, undated (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Appointment books, 1940 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Articles about Kenneth Simpson and other biographical information, 1937-1946, undated (Box 33, Folder 3 - 4)
  - Family papers
    - Hamlin, Sarah H. J. Simpson estate, 1930-1931 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Porter, Caroline K. C. estate, undated (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Simpson, Helen
      - General, 1941-1951 (Box 33, Folder 7)
      - Coordinating Committee for Democratic Action, 1941 (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Simpson, William K. [father], 1914, 1916 (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Simpson children, 1946-1948, 1983 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Financial papers
    - General, Circa 1936-1940 (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - Account book of expenses, 1937-1938 (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - Account book for investments, 1938-1939 (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - Check counterfoils, 1925-1926 (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - Check counterfoils, 1931-1937 (Box 34, Folder 15 - 18)
  - Legal papers
    - Barnes, Richardson, and Halstead, 1931, 1933-1935 (Box 34, Folder 19)
    - Hunt, Hill, and Betts, 1934-1939 (Box 34, Folder 20)
    - Loburn Realty Corporation vs. Simpson, 1932-1933 (Box 34, Folder 21)
  - Memorabilia
    - General, 1900, 1920s-1940, undated (Box 34, Folder 22 - 24)
      - Oversize, 1922 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Friendly Sons of St. Patrick, 1936-1940 (Box 35, Folder 25 - 29)
    - Gridiron Club, 1936-1940 (Box 35, Folder 30)
    - Inner Circle, 1937-1940 (Box 35, Folder 31)
    - Legislative Correspondents Association, 1936-1940 (Box 35, Folder 32)
    - New York World's Fair, 1939 (Box 35, Folder 33)
    - Presidential inauguration, 1941 (Box 35, Folder 34)
    - Republican Party, 1936-1940 (Box 36, Folder 35)
    - Skull and Bones, 1916-1922, 1938 (Box 36, Folder 36)
    - St. James Church (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Photographs
    - 1934 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - 1936-1937 (Box 36, Folder 37)
    - 1938-1939 (Box 36, Folder 38)
    - 1940 (Box 36, Folder 39)
    - undated (Box 36, Folder 40)
    - Colleagues and friends, 1927, undated (Box 36, Folder 41)
    - Family, 1936-1939, undated (Box 36, Folder 42)
    - Portraits, 1937, undated (Box 36, Folder 43)
    - Oversize, 1934-1940 (Box 37, Folder 6)
- Scrapbooks, 1925-1941; Series VI
  The nine scrapbooks of newspaper clippings in this series provide very thorough coverage of Simpson's role in New York politics from 1937-1940. They focus on the "Fusion" candidates in the New York City mayoral election of 1937, Fiorello LaGuardia and Thomas Dewey, the growing power struggle within the New York State Republican Party, and Simpson's split with the party's majority over Dewey's candidacy for the presidential nomination in 1940. The scrapbooks also document the Wilkie campaign and Simpson's own election to Congress in 1940. The original scrapbooks were microfilmed in 1981 and 2002 and the fragile originals discarded.
  - 1. "The New York Mayoral Elections, 1937"
    Mayoral candidates were: incumbent Fiorello La Guardia, United States Senator Royal Copeland and Jeremiah Mahoney. Thomas Dewey elected as District Attorney. Simpson's role in support of La Guardia's nomination by the Republican Party.
  - 2. "The New York Mayoral Elections, 1937", 1935 October - 1937 June
    Divisions in the New York State Republican Party. Contest for 1936 Presidential nomination of Republican candidate within New York State.
  - 3. "The 1937 Elections and Dewey's First Successful Entry into Politics", 1937 July - August
    New York Mayoral contest, 1937. La Guardia seeks Republican nomination. Thomas Dewey, Special Prosecutor, sought as "Fusion Candidate" for District Attorney, receives Republican nomination.
  - 4. "Power Struggles with Dewey in New York State Republican Party, 1938-1940", 1938 November - 1940 March
    Internal struggle within the New York State Republican Party. Dewey promoted as Republican candidate for President, 1940 election.
  - 5. "National Republican Resurgence, 1938-1940", 1938 September - 1940 March
    Various editorials concerning the role of Kenneth Simpson in the Republican Party and the Party itself. Struggle within the Party between the "liberals" and the "Old Guard."
  - 6. "Power Struggles for Republican Nomination for President for 1940", 1940 April - July
    Rift in New York State Republican Party. Simpson's split with Dewey. Wendell Wilkie receives Presidential nomination; supported by Simpson.
  - 7. "Republican Politics of 1940", 1940 April - October
    Controversy within the New York State Republican Party; mounting opposition to Dewey.
  - 8. "Simpson's Last Days as New York State Republican Chairman", 1940 October - December
  - 9. "Simpson's Election to Congress of 1941", 1940 October - 1941 February
    Campaign coverage; Simpson wins election to Congress as Representative from 17th Congressional District, New York. Wendell Wilkie the Republican Presidential candidate; Bruce Barton the candidate for Senator from New York.
  - 10. Untitled, 1925-1938
  - 11. Untitled, 1936 January-1937 October
  - 12. Untitled, 1937 October-1938 November